<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://tomoslau.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://tomoslau.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-17T16:08:49+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tom Lau</title><subtitle>I'm Tom Lau, a designer based in Hong Kong working with startups and businesses to build amazing products.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">HYPEBEAST</title><link href="http://tomoslau.com/hypebeast-mobile-redesign/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HYPEBEAST" /><published>2018-08-12T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-08-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/hypebeast-mobile-redesign</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tomoslau.com/hypebeast-mobile-redesign/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hypebeast.com&quot;&gt;HYPEBEAST&lt;/a&gt; is a media platform for youth culture to get the latest news in streetwear, sneakers, fashion, entertainment and music. Our readers get their dose of hype through social media, website, and app. Of these channels, our most loyal readers use the app. In turn, readers who download the app have increased retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to increase our loyal readership by improving the mobile app reading experience and marketing. During 2017 and 2018, I redesigned HYPEBEAST’s mobile apps to foster a better reading experience. Below are a few changes we shipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-a-more-familiar-experience-for-both-platforms&quot;&gt;Creating a more familiar experience for both platforms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I joined the team, HYPEBEAST’s Android app was designed and developed to mimic the iOS counterpart. The prioritization to design for iOS only was due to the 80% iOS and 20% Android monthly active users split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This created an &lt;strong&gt;unfamiliar interactive and visual experience&lt;/strong&gt; for our Android readers, as well as a &lt;strong&gt;reduction in app performance&lt;/strong&gt; due to custom components and animations based on iOS. Furthermore, Google Play refused to feature our app due to several usability and visual issues addressed in the Material Design guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-material.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Application of Material Design patterns to the Android app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make our app less confusing for our app readers, &lt;strong&gt;we utilized patterns shared by both iOS and Android platforms, while conforming to Human Interface Guidelines and Material Design specs.&lt;/strong&gt; We applied Jakob’s law by ensuring our app works the the same way as all the other apps they use. For example, both apps share a bottom tab bar as the primary navigation, but details such as the bar height, shadow “elevation”, and transitions differed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We used native components and system icons wherever possible.&lt;/strong&gt; By removing custom components and animations, such as the app bar and iOS-style “back” transition, the Android app felt more snappy and familiar according to our testers. This resulted in a &amp;lt;400ms (Doherty Threshold) interaction feedback on lower end devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improving-readability-andfocus&quot;&gt;Improving readability and focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We received feedback from our readers and internally that our app looks dated. This is apparent when compared to our competitors and other apps. Instead of simply following the minimalism trend, we decided to take this opportunity to improve readability and focus as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;News feed: before and after&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We avoided long headlines on images&lt;/strong&gt; for articles where editors and designers don’t have control over placement and styling. Previously, the gradient overlays made images too dark, covered parts of images, and sometimes created undesirable visuals. The revised design allows both headline and image to be clear, and also uses the same assets across mobile, tablet and desktop designs to simplify editors’ workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-style.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visual styling revisited&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-components.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;App components&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We revisited the typography to &lt;strong&gt;create a stronger hierarchy&lt;/strong&gt;. Readers can identify important news and sponsored posts based on prominence. We reduced the complexity of icons to make them more recognizable. We also implemented new color guidelines to improve contrast and meet WCAG guidelines, and a soft 8-point grid to create vertical rhythm, consistent spacing and increased proximity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-natural-and-familiar-gesture-controls&quot;&gt;More natural and familiar gesture controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In usability tests, we noticed readers trying to use certain gesture controls, but the app failed to do their desired action. Some gestures are not native to the platform but are so common in popular apps that readers expect them to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1d6cTwAg_cM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we learned that many iOS readers didn’t know that tapping on the status bar scrolls to top. Instead, they tried to scroll to top by tapping on the bottom bar again. We added this gesture control to both platforms. We also made sure all the tabs were swipeable, and image galleries can be closed based on vertical gestures (flicking away).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our readers love reading article comments. However, navigating from comments back to the article was difficult on iOS. Due to the limitations with Disqus, we loaded the comments on a separate page. Previously, this was presented as a full page modal, with a close button on the top bar away from the thumb zone. Android readers didn’t have this problem because it could be closed by tapping the back button. To make it easier to navigate, we changed the comments page so it pushed in from the right, and added the familiar swipe back gesture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since shipping these updates, our app reviews improved, and the app was featured on Google Play and the App Store. In 2017, we grew from 32k to 73k monthly active users.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">HYPEBEAST is a media platform for youth culture to get the latest news in streetwear, sneakers, fashion, entertainment and music. Our readers get their dose of hype through social media, website, and app. Of these channels, our most loyal readers use the app. In turn, readers who download the app have increased retention.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jook</title><link href="http://tomoslau.com/jook/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jook" /><published>2017-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/jook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tomoslau.com/jook/">&lt;p&gt;Jook is a side project I’ve been working on with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Kahou526&quot;&gt;Lucas Kuan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MaBoXiu&quot;&gt;Matthieu Bodin&lt;/a&gt;. I focus on design, front-end web development, user testing, and data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discovering-the-problem&quot;&gt;Discovering the problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our project spawned from a specific problem my colleagues and I faced during the summer of 2015. Lucas, Matthieu and I worked in a small office room. &lt;strong&gt;We loved playing music on speakers while we worked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-office.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our office&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The set up was simple. Matthieu hooked up his computer to the speakers, and played music on Spotify. Although we shared similar tastes in music, Lucas and I would make song requests whenever we felt like a change of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did we feel the urge to change the music?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To share music that we like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To have a sense of control, a voice/opinion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To change the mood by playing something different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks, we sensed that &lt;strong&gt;requesting songs became disruptive to our work.&lt;/strong&gt; We tried sending Spotify links on Slack to make it easier for Matthieu, but it still felt disruptive. We tried using a shared playlist on Spotify, but it didn’t feel spontaneous. &lt;strong&gt;What if we could each queue songs from our own devices without bothering each other?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Four years at art school and I still can’t draw straight lines.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to build an app to do that—a jukebox for our office room that uses Spotify’s API. As we designed and developed the prototype, we realized that we could use the jukebox app outside of the office—for things like parties and startup events that we organized or attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-flow.png&quot; alt=&quot;Initial host and guest diagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The host is responsible for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hosting the jukebox through the app.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inviting guests by sharing the jukebox link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learns about the jukebox at the event.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opens the link to jukebox on browser (no log-in required to reduce friction), and sees the song currently playing and queued songs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adds songs to the queue and upvote songs added by others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-web.png&quot; alt=&quot;Web app screenshots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a small party, the host can easily tell everyone about the jukebox, and share a link to them through a group chat. At larger events, this becomes more tricky. Strangers are less likely to try something new, so broadcasting it is not as easy. We later learned from hosts that &lt;strong&gt;guests favor using the host’s device&lt;/strong&gt; to add songs instead of using their own. Many requested for a tablet version of the app to make this easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-swhk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We tested Jook at a Startup Weekend event by word of mouth and handouts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;↑ One of our first tests at a Startup Weekend event by word of mouth and handouts (like the one on this table above the Subway napkin).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing&quot;&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tested Jook whenever possible—at the office, events, and parties. Getting organizers to host a jukebox turned out to be easier than we thought. After observing and talking to guests and hosts, this is what we learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users felt the need to keep adding songs&lt;/strong&gt; when their jukebox ran out of songs in the queue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They spent a lot of time &lt;strong&gt;stuck at the search bar&lt;/strong&gt; thinking of what song to add.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They often opened Spotify to find a song from their library, and then went back to Jook to search the song.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At large events, hosts noticed that &lt;strong&gt;guests prefer to walk up to and use the host’s device&lt;/strong&gt; (ie. an iPad) rather than manually typing in the url when a share link is not sent to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features-we-added-prior-to-public-beta&quot;&gt;Features we added prior to public beta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fallback playlist&lt;/strong&gt;: where the host can select a playlist to fallback on when there are no songs left in the queue, so that the jukebox will never run out of songs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drag-and-drop songs from Spotify&lt;/strong&gt; directly to Jook on web browser.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preview song snippets before adding them to the jukebox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-app.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We added a fallback playlist feature so the jukebox will never run out of songs to play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also added a prominent “Send Feedback” button to encourage our users to send us valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since releasing Jook, hosts have created more than 500 jukeboxes with over 5,000 guests. We learned several things from our users:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-they-loved&quot;&gt;What they loved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An easy way to play everyone’s favorite music in an environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Voting songs is fun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ease of adding songs on desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-they-struggled-with&quot;&gt;What they struggled with&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finding songs to add on mobile (no drag-and-drop in app or mobile web)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not knowing that a Spotify Premium account is needed to host a jukebox (high drop-off rate on login screen in app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-they-asked-for&quot;&gt;What they asked for&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Downvote to drop unpopular songs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow hosts to remove songs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explicit songs filter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all the users who helped us test the product and gave us amazing feedback. We’re continuously looking at feedback and data from our lovely users, and working towards an update.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Jook is a side project I’ve been working on with Lucas Kuan and Matthieu Bodin. I focus on design, front-end web development, user testing, and data analysis.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bupa</title><link href="http://tomoslau.com/bupa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bupa" /><published>2016-11-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/bupa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tomoslau.com/bupa/">&lt;p&gt;Between May and November of 2016, I worked on Bupa Hong Kong’s new website as Art Director at Isobar. I designed the visual interface and worked closely with the UX team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bupa is a healthcare group headquartered in the United Kingdom. It expanded into Hong Kong in 1976 and has been a health insurance and healthcare provision business since. Their audience is professional individuals and companies looking for a healthcare plan for their employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discovery&quot;&gt;Discovery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reviewed feedback on the current site and discovered that &lt;strong&gt;customers found it difficult to find a suitable insurance plan&lt;/strong&gt;. We did an analysis and found several problems: product names were vague and non-descriptive, the wide range of plans and broad categories were hard to browse, and the website wasn’t mobile-optimized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We brainstormed on how to make it easier for customers to find a suitable plan, and proceeded with the idea of &lt;strong&gt;giving recommendations and quotations based on a simple form&lt;/strong&gt;. We added a form on the home page where customers fill in a few fields and immediately get three recommended plans. They can choose to refine the pricing by adding more information and enroll the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-flow.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beginning steps are the simplest, and with each step the flow becomes more specific and there is more information and data input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Input a few pieces of information to receive three recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compare and select a plan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refine the quotation by choosing payment and plan options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Long form for personal details and a series of yes/no health questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Payment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-desktop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Medical insurance plans and quotation engine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We designed the recommended plans view to be in the same style as regular cards, but expanded vertically to show more information. The information is divided into sections and displayed in an underlying grid so the same information can be &lt;strong&gt;easily scanned&lt;/strong&gt; across all three plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early feedback and testing of the wireframes showed that many customers found the forms &lt;strong&gt;long and overwhelming&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to breaking up the long forms into smaller chunks and steps, we tested the idea of using placeholders as labels. Bupa and our team were initially drawn to this idea because it made the forms appear less overwhelming—the forms looked “cleaner” and the reduced vertical space meant less scroll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the density of Traditional Chinese characters, labels are easier to read in a larger size and lighter weight than smaller size and heavier weight. Material Design recommends increasing “Dense scripts” by 1 point from the specified size for English. This adds more vertical space for Chinese form labels, plus &lt;strong&gt;exaggerates the visual density&lt;/strong&gt; when compared to using placeholders as labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, using placeholders as labels create a number of usability problems, as summarized by Katie Sherwin of Nielsen Norman Group. Here are the top three reasons that applied to the forms we were designing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strains short-term memory&lt;/strong&gt;: users have to delete what they wrote to reveal the placeholder label again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users cannot check their input with the label&lt;/strong&gt; (especially important for browsers with autocomplete)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empty vs non-empty fields are less noticeable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-labels.png&quot; alt=&quot;Traditional labels, placeholder labels and float labels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We compromised by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/r/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fmds.is%2Ffloat-label-pattern%2F&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;float labels&lt;/a&gt;. Float labels allow the empty form to appear more clean and less overwhelming, while solving the usability problems of placeholder labels to a certain extent. When asked which form looks less overwhelming, most customers picked the one with float labels over labels on top of fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-form.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enrollment form&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website launched in early 2017. Bupa loved the brand new clean, simple and functional design. The new website increased sales leads by 200% and online purchases by 300%.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Between May and November of 2016, I worked on Bupa Hong Kong’s new website as Art Director at Isobar. I designed the visual interface and worked closely with the UX team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy Owl</title><link href="http://tomoslau.com/happy-owl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy Owl" /><published>2016-07-01T15:33:10+08:00</published><updated>2016-07-01T15:33:10+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/happy-owl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tomoslau.com/happy-owl/">&lt;p&gt;I joined Happy Owl in May 2016 to design a minimum viable product.  Happy Owl aimed to solve partner bars and restaurants’ problem of &lt;strong&gt;a lack of customers during non-peak hours&lt;/strong&gt;. We increased traffic by &lt;strong&gt;offering one drink per day to customers at a low monthly price&lt;/strong&gt; at any of the venues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discovery&quot;&gt;Discovery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking to potential users, we found that the most likely paying customers are 25–35 young professionals working in finance. When it comes to going out for drinks with friends and colleagues, the first decision they make is &lt;strong&gt;the district&lt;/strong&gt; (most prefer Central for its proximity to offices). Other factors include the venue’s atmosphere, and type of drinks and food provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first version of the flow, we prioritized the district selection, map view, and venue list with clear images and description. We also added nearby venues, a secondary flow for users who want to discover bars on the go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ho-discovery-wireframes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Owl discovery wireframes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drink-redemption-experience&quot;&gt;Drink redemption experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drink redemption process required:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clear instructions&lt;/strong&gt; for the member to pass their phone to the venue staff.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The redeem action &lt;strong&gt;cannot be easily triggered&lt;/strong&gt; by accident.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The redeem action is &lt;strong&gt;easy enough so the staff can be trained&lt;/strong&gt; quickly (training our 40+ venues was time intensive for our operations team.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ho-wireframes-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Owl drink redemption flow wireframes&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ho-redeem-flow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Owl drink redemption flow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;identity-design&quot;&gt;Identity design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our visual identity is fun, friendly, and energetic. The user colors in the user interface is kept to a minimal to make the photography pop. The photos capture the vibrant experiences of different venues and having fun with friends. We used a dark theme for the UI design, as the app is primarily used in dark environments at night. The accent yellow color creates contrast with the dark interface and resembles beer. Our typographic approach makes use of geometry and roundness to reflect the brand’s personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ho-colors.png&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Owl color palette&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ho-type.png&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Owl typography&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sketching dozens and dozens of owls, we decided to work with a playful owl face that fills the square picture plane to create a visually compelling and functional design. We applied our brand’s bright blue and pink colors (inspired by Hong Kong nightlife and neon signs) to the owl, which also mimics Asian flush to add a bit of humor to the character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ho-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Owl logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ho-icons.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Drinks illustration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ho.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Owl app mockups&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We released the app in July 2016 and threw a launch party at Zuma (featuring an owl ice luge.) With the help of event promotions, word of mouth and media coverage, we reached over 1,000 downloads and 300 paying subscribers by the end of the first month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Owl was featured on the App Store and named &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/food-drink/article/2055131/four-handy-apps-hong-kongs-drinkers-and-party-people&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one of four handy apps for Hong Kong drinkers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ho-event.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Happy Owl launch event&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I joined Happy Owl in May 2016 to design a minimum viable product. Happy Owl aimed to solve partner bars and restaurants’ problem of a lack of customers during non-peak hours. We increased traffic by offering one drink per day to customers at a low monthly price at any of the venues.</summary></entry></feed>