<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://happygoodhorse.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://happygoodhorse.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-19T20:36:17+08:00</updated><id>http://happygoodhorse.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tom Lau</title><subtitle>I'm Tom Lau, product designer in Hong Kong currently building crowdsourced delivery at GogoX</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Designing the mobile same-day delivery experience</title><link href="http://happygoodhorse.com/gogox-mobile-delivery-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Designing the mobile same-day delivery experience" /><published>2020-09-24T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-09-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://happygoodhorse.com/gogox-delivery-mobile-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happygoodhorse.com/gogox-mobile-delivery-experience/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GogoX is Hong Kong’s largest on-demand logistics platform (think Uber for logistics) and operates in Taiwan, Singapore, India, Vietnam, and South Korea. In 2018, GogoX launched a new service to tackle same-day last-mile delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to increase delivery demand while maintaining a high completion rate on the supply side. In this case study, we’ll focus on the activation and retention on the demand side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;role&quot;&gt;Role&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior Product Designer: User research, interaction, visual design, prototyping, testing, design QA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;problem&quot;&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GogoX’s client app went through a revamp in late 2019. Due to constraints, components and flows were shared across both vehicle hiring and delivery services. After launching the new app, we decided to tackle the conversion in the place order flow to increase activation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the order funnel data and user interviews, we discovered opportunities to improve the conversion for entering sender and recipient and package information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F1F1;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;max-width:320px;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggd-mobile-place-order-before.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Video of the old Delivery place order flow&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on surveys I conducted and calls by the customer service team, we found the most frequently mentioned pain points were the completion rate and the amount of information to fill in on the order form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To dig deeper into their pain points, I conducted qualitative user interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It feels like there are a lot of steps to enter the sender and recipient information. It’s also difficult to edit the address.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s a lot of input compared to other delivery services. For example, other services have a fixed rate and I don’t have to enter the package information like size and weight every time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sometimes I find it difficult to find an address. I usually copy and paste my customer’s address, but sometimes there are no search results.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;competitive-analysis&quot;&gt;Competitive analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-mobile-competitor-analysis.png&quot; alt=&quot;Competitor analysis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we placed our order flow next to our competitors’ and other on-demand delivery services’, it’s apparent there are more steps in our flow, especially in the sender/recipient details and package information steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brainstorm&quot;&gt;Brainstorm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-mobile-brainstorm.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brainstorm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shared the research and facilitated a brainstorm session with our cross-functional team to tackle the two steps of the funnel. Then, I took our favorite ideas and prototyped them to test with ad-hoc users and merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;simplified-the-senderrecipient-form&quot;&gt;Simplified the sender/recipient form&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F1F1;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;max-width:320px;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggd-mobile-from-to-form-prototype.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Prototype exploring the idea of a single page form&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F1F1;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;max-width:320px;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggd-mobile-from-to-late-prototype.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Prototype of new sender/recipient details and address input flow&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-from-to-before.png&quot; alt=&quot;From and to before&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-from-to-after.png&quot; alt=&quot;From and to after&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on usability tests, we found that the design that shows all the details for sender/recipient in a single page provided the most clarity to merchants. It allowed merchants to review their input and edit any field easier. The new form also prefilled the sender’s address using the device’s location as this was the most frequent use case based on data and interviews. The address details, sender name and phone number are also filled if there’s available information from their account details or a previous order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;select-on-map&quot;&gt;Select on map&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-select-on-map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Select on map shipped&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;What we shipped for the first scope&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-select-on-map-alt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Select on map alt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Exploration on an idea suggested by our engineer Jay to suggest nearby addresses&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During usability tests, we found that the GPS location taken to prefill the sender’s address isn’t always accurate, especially in dense cities. To tackle this issue, we shipped a select on map feature to allow merchants to drag their location on the map to refine their pickup or dropoff location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;package-information&quot;&gt;Package information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F1F1;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;max-width:320px;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggd-mobile-package-info-prototype-1.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Prototype of linking size and weight to package types based on historical data&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F1F1;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;max-width:320px;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggd-mobile-package-info-prototype-2.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Prototype of the Business flow with custom size and weight input (unlinked from package type)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-package-info-before.png&quot; alt=&quot;Package info before&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-package-info-after.png&quot; alt=&quot;Package info after&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;What we shipped for Personal and Business users&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-package-info-autofill.png&quot; alt=&quot;Package info autofill&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;We also shipped autofill using merchants' previously entered package information&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package information page was the second-highest dropoff point for new and ad-hoc users. Through user interviews, we learned that most ad-hoc users felt the package information took a long time to fill in. Most of them expected to be able to send a package as long as it fits under a size that fits in a motorbike or sedan, and found it unnecessary to fill in the details. Merchants, though, didn’t mind filling in the details like package size and weight because they are price-sensitive. In fact, many merchants we spoke with felt our box model options (i.e. within a 40x40x40cm cube) were too restrictive when they wanted to send flatter and longer packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to create a different package information form for new/ad-hoc users, and merchants based on their needs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For ad-hoc users, we simplified the 20 possible size and weight combinations to two options (40x40x40cm, 10kg, and 60x60x60cm, 20kg) based on the size and weight relationship from historical orders and competitive advantages. I conducted interviews and comparative usability tests to validate laypeople’s mental model on communicating the size and weight of packages. I found that the existing box model (i.e. 40x40x40cm) is easier to understand than using combined dimensions or volumetric weight (common in the logistics industry) and most people guess the size and weight instead of measuring with tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the merchant’s flow, we added separate input fields for length, width, and height to give businesses the flexibility to send long and narrow packages at a fairer price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both flows, we introduced package info defaults for new users and reused previous order information for returning users. We also added a saved package feature, where merchants can autofill the package information page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outcome&quot;&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;28% users selected a pickup or dropoff on the map&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Address confirmed increased by 125%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The conversion between starting an order and completing the sender/recipient details increased by 8%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time spent on package info page reduced by 14% (after autofill rollout and before new package info flow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learnings&quot;&gt;Learnings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months after rolling out the sender/recipient flow, our operations team received an increase in courier complaints regarding the accuracy of pickup addresses. Our assumption is that by prefilling the pickup location using the device’s GPS, some users may not be aware they should change it when the address is wrong. This resulted in couriers going to the wrong location and spending more time communicating with clients. A good problem to solve given the impact of the solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Overview</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building the delivery experience for small and medium-sized merchants</title><link href="http://happygoodhorse.com/gogox-delivery-experience-for-merchants/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building the delivery experience for small and medium-sized merchants" /><published>2020-01-25T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-01-25T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://happygoodhorse.com/gogox-delivery-for-merchants</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happygoodhorse.com/gogox-delivery-experience-for-merchants/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;role&quot;&gt;Role&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gogo Delivery for business was a result of the continuous discovery that our PM and I conducted. I led user interviews, conducted surveys, and worked closely with our data analysts to learn more about our users on a regular basis. Based on our learnings, our PM and I defined product strategies that align with our business goals. From there, we defined hypotheses and metrics. I worked closely with engineers and the cross-functional team throughout the ideation and prototyping phase, sought feedback from designers via weekly critiques, and tested prototypes with merchants. For the final deliverables, I worked with designers who work on our Client mobile app and web app to align the UI and interaction, update the Design System if needed, and verify the translations. I discussed the design with engineers and QA during grooming, and design QA’ed before launch. Post-launch, we reviewed the metrics and retrospected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After launching Gogo Delivery on mobile, we found that a small percentage of our users created a large percentage of orders. Through data and user interviews, we learned that these users were merchants selling food and beverages, beauty products, electronics, and pet products. We segmented these merchants into two groups based on their behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ad-hoc&quot;&gt;Ad hoc&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Places deliveries when needed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Requires urgent delivery (like food and medicine)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the go, prefers to use mobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;batch&quot;&gt;Batch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consolidates orders and places orders the day before or in the morning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doesn’t require urgent delivery (like wine and electronics)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Usually sits behind a computer to manage orders on e-commerce platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pain-points&quot;&gt;Pain points&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pain points prioritized by severity (in bold) and frequency (highlighted in orange and yellow)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-web-user-journey.png&quot; alt=&quot;User journey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-strategy&quot;&gt;Product strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on our continuous discovery learnings, we defined what our product should achieve for ad hoc and batch merchants to support our business objectives&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a web app that is seamless with the mobile experience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplify the flow for repeat orders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enhance the experience for batch deliveries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Help merchants manage multiple orders easier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow merchants to add team members under one account and view monthly reports to save time on expensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-app&quot;&gt;Web app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the initial scope, we created a web app with the same functionalities as our mobile app so that merchants who work on a desktop can place and manage orders easier (such as copy and pasting delivery information from their e-commerce platform). The desktop real estate enabled us to create a single form for placing an order without going back and forth between screens, and a table view for managing orders easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-place-order.png&quot; alt=&quot;Place order screens&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-order-management.png&quot; alt=&quot;Order management screens&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
--&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F1F1;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggb-place-order.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Place order flow&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F1F1;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggb-order-management.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Order management&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;simplified-repeat-orders&quot;&gt;Simplified repeat orders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We observed merchants placing orders and found that they tend to deliver items to frequent customers with similar package information. Some of the merchants even used the native mobile keyboard shortcuts to fill in the order form easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help merchants place orders, we enabled autofill for the sender, recipient, and package information so that they can fill in most of the form in a few clicks without inputting each field individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-autofill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Autofill order information&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also launched “reuse order” under order details so merchants can request an order with the same details easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-reuse-details.png&quot; alt=&quot;Reuse order details&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bulk-order&quot;&gt;Bulk order&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned that merchants who consolidate orders and batch delivery orders manage their orders internally using spreadsheets. Some of them sold products on several different platforms, like Shopify, Shopline, and Price. They export spreadsheets from these platforms and combine the orders into one spreadsheet for management. They were also familiar with using bulk spreadsheet import on other logistic platforms. During user interviews, we learned more about their likes and dislikes on the bulk importing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges when designing this feature was balancing the error handling experience with technical effort. Our engineers and I narrowed down to three options, from the lowest to highest effort and worst to best experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Returning a list of errors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generate a CSV with errors on a new column&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Display errors in an editable table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I showed these prototypes to merchants, their main concern was the validation handling for the addresses (a limitation with using Google Places) and drop-off times (due to cut-off time rules). We decided to launch a version that simply returns a list of errors to a closed beta group first, while simultaneously working on the editable table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-bulk-flows.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bulk order flows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A comparison between the low effort and the ideal flow. In phase 1, merchants are required to go back and forth between spreadsheet and the list of errors to amend errors before uploading again - an existing pain point for merchants who use other products. The editable table allows merchants to directly amend errors on the table.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reduce errors before import, we added data validation on the spreadsheet template. We also added examples at the top to help first-time users understand what to enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-bulk-excel.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bulk order Excel file&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;An example of a filled template with data validation errors (marked with a red corner)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-bulk-validation-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bulk order validation v1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Phase 1: Returned list of errors. In this example, the address is invalid, and backend returns a list of valid suggestions so merchants can copy the correct address and paste in their spreadsheet before importing again.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F1F1;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggb-bulk-order-spreadsheet.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Bulk order spreadsheet&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F1F1;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggb-bulk-order.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Bulk order import shipped for phase 2 with editable table for merchants to amend any invalid fields&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!--
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-bulk-validation-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bulk order validation v2&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Phase 2: Editable table. Cells with errors are marked in red. Merchants can edit the values directly on the table. In this example, one of the addresses is invalid, and the merchant can select a valid address from the dropdown.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our store visits and taking orders as couriers, we found that many merchants wrote the recipient district and pick-up verification code on labels or directly on the packages. To aid this process, we introduced shipping labels that merchants can choose to print after placing their orders. Interestingly, when we tested this with merchants, some said they still preferred to hand-write to save the environment and printing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-package-labels-writing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Merchant's handwritten notes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Examples of merchant's handwritten notes to aid package management and pick-up process. Most merchants wrote down the recipient district (what couriers look for when collecting packages) and the pick-up code (what couriers look for to verify package pick-up) &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-label-markup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shipping label markup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Shipping label design&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggb-print-labels.png&quot; alt=&quot;Printing shipping labels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Merchants can print shipping labels after placing batch deliveries.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outcome&quot;&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Package information autofill reduced time spent on the order form by 23%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reuse order contributed to 93% increase in orders placed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;65% merchants print shipping labels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Role</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Helping couriers find more relevant delivery orders</title><link href="http://happygoodhorse.com/gogox-courier-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Helping couriers find more relevant delivery orders" /><published>2019-07-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-07-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://happygoodhorse.com/gogox-delivery-courier</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happygoodhorse.com/gogox-courier-experience/">&lt;p&gt;Nine months into launching Gogo Delivery (a crowd-sourced delivery service), the demand grew to a point where the supply couldn’t keep up. Couriers were scrolling through a long list of orders to find orders to take. Response time increased and completion rate dropped. To improve this, our team pivoted our objective to improve courier activation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-role&quot;&gt;My role&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I led the design for courier experience. I worked closely with our PM, FE and BE enginers, Data Analyst, and cross-functional team (Operations, Customer Service, Marketing) throughout the design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through user interviews and focus groups, we found that couriers had &lt;strong&gt;difficulty in finding relevant orders&lt;/strong&gt;. A few months earlier, when there was less demand, there were only around twenty pending orders that couriers can pick from at a given time. Now, there’s over a hundred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned that couriers select orders based on distance from pick up location, drop off location and earnings. To empathize with our couriers, our team went out and delivered packages. This enabled further learnings such as order bundling planning to maximize travel efficiency and earnings, and package size and weight considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-sprint&quot;&gt;Design sprint&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I led a design sprint with cross-functional teams to identify the key problems to tackle for courier activation and decide which ideas to test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-courier-finding-orders-sketches.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sketches from the design sprint to tackle couriers' problem of finding relevant orders&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Sketches from the design sprint to tackle couriers' problem of finding relevant orders&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;most-popular-idea-order-bundling-suggestion&quot;&gt;Most popular idea: Order bundling suggestion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;max-width:960px;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;source src=&quot;https://cdn.dribbble.com/users/611270/videos/23476/20190424-courier-map-3.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Early prototype to explore suggested bundling for couriers&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We explored the most popular idea: a visual map to show couriers available orders based on their location and suggesting bundling to increase efficiency and income. However, due to the technical scope of this idea, we chose not to pursue this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;order-suggestions&quot;&gt;Order suggestions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-courier-order-suggestions.png&quot; alt=&quot;Push notifications for new orders based on proximity to active orders&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Push notifications for new orders based on proximity to active order&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Couriers tend to pick orders that are “on the way.” We tested the idea of sending push notifications for new orders to active couriers based on their orders’ pick up and drop off locations. This enables them to find orders they’re interested in without opening the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;order-filtering&quot;&gt;Order filtering&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-courier-filters-flow.png&quot; alt=&quot;Courier flow for filtering and sorting available orders&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Courier flow for filtering and sorting available orders&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also explored using filters and sorting to help couriers find relevant orders. We tested the prototype with couriers and made several iterations to suit their needs and technical constraints. The final design uses a sticky top bar with dropdown menus to indicate active filters (in a different color) and the sorting method at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;max-width:960px;margin:0 auto&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/gogo-delivery-courier-filters.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Prototype for pick up region, drop off region filters and sorting by time, distance to pick up and earnings&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shipped the order filtering and sorting first. We assumed this had the greatest outcome for couriers due to their strong preference of picking orders by region and earnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-filters&quot;&gt;Additional filters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-courier-filters-add.png&quot; alt=&quot;Additional filters for time, package size, and weight&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Additional filters for time, package size, and weight&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we shipped filters for time constraints, package size, and weight. This enabled couriers to further filter orders that are more relevant to them - for example, package weights that they are physically capable of carrying when bundling orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outcome&quot;&gt;Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Daily orders by adopters increased 180%&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Response time reduced 83%&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learnings&quot;&gt;Learnings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During product discovery, we learned that region filters are more impactful than size, weight, and time filters. After launch, we found that the pick up region filter had less usage than the other filters. Our assumptions are that couriers are constantly travelling, so changing the pick up filter is too interaction costly. Also the defined region polygons may be too geographically large to be helpful. This is something that we missed due to interviewing and testing with couriers in a de-contextualized/scripted environment. We can improve by using research methods that involve natural use of the product, such as ethnographic field studies or testing a prototype that can be used with real orders in a real environment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Nine months into launching Gogo Delivery (a crowd-sourced delivery service), the demand grew to a point where the supply couldn’t keep up. Couriers were scrolling through a long list of orders to find orders to take. Response time increased and completion rate dropped. To improve this, our team pivoted our objective to improve courier activation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Improving the reading experience for millions of streetwear enthusiasts around the world</title><link href="http://happygoodhorse.com/2018/08/12/hypebeast-mobile-redesign.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Improving the reading experience for millions of streetwear enthusiasts around the world" /><published>2018-08-12T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-08-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://happygoodhorse.com/2018/08/12/hypebeast-mobile-redesign</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happygoodhorse.com/2018/08/12/hypebeast-mobile-redesign.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hypebeast.com&quot;&gt;Hypebeast&lt;/a&gt; is a media platform for youth culture to get the latest news in streetwear, sneakers, fashion, entertainment and music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to increase our loyal readership by improving the mobile app reading experience. During 2017 and 2018, I redesigned Hypebeast’s mobile apps to foster a better reading experience. Below are a few changes we shipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-a-more-familiar-experience-for-both-platforms&quot;&gt;Creating a more familiar experience for both platforms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypebeast’s Android app was designed to mimic the iOS counterpart. This created an &lt;strong&gt;unfamiliar interactive and visual experience&lt;/strong&gt; for our Android readers, as well as a &lt;strong&gt;reduction in app performance&lt;/strong&gt; due to custom components and animations based on iOS. Furthermore, Google Play refused to feature our app due to several usability and visual issues addressed in the Material Design guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-drops-platforms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Application of Material Design patterns to the Android app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make our app less confusing for our app readers, &lt;strong&gt;we utilized patterns shared by both iOS and Android platforms, while conforming to Human Interface Guidelines and Material Design specs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We used native components and system icons wherever possible.&lt;/strong&gt; By removing custom components and animations, such as the app bar and iOS-style “back” transition, the Android app’s performance increased and felt more snappy and familiar to our readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improving-readability-andfocus&quot;&gt;Improving readability and focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We received feedback from our readers that our app looks dated. This was apparent when compared to our competitors and other apps. Instead of simply following the minimalism trend, we decided to take this opportunity to improve readability and focus as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-home-article.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;News feed and article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We avoided long headlines on images&lt;/strong&gt; for articles where editors and designers don’t have control over placement and styling. Previously, the gradient overlays made images too dark, covered parts of images, and sometimes created undesirable visuals. The revised design allows both headline and image to be clear, and also uses the same assets across mobile, tablet and desktop designs to simplify editors’ workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-style.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visual styling revisited&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We revisited the typography to &lt;strong&gt;create a stronger hierarchy&lt;/strong&gt;. Readers can identify important news and sponsored posts based on prominence. We reduced the complexity of icons to make them more recognizable. We also implemented new color guidelines to improve contrast and meet WCAG guidelines, and a soft 8-point grid to create vertical rhythm, consistent spacing and increased proximity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-components.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;App components&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-natural-and-familiar-gesture-controls&quot;&gt;More natural and familiar gesture controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In usability tests, we noticed readers trying to use certain gesture controls based on their experience with other popular apps, but the app failed to do their desired action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/hb-gestures.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Gesture interactions based on what readers expected&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we learned that many iOS readers didn’t know that tapping on the status bar scrolls to top. Instead, they tried to scroll to top by tapping on the bottom bar again. We added this gesture control to both platforms. We also made sure all the tabs were swipeable, and image galleries can be closed by flicking it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since shipping these updates, our app reviews improved, and the app was featured on Google Play and the App Store. In 2017, we grew from 32k to 73k monthly active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-home-devices.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hypebeast app on mobile and tablet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hypebeast is a media platform for youth culture to get the latest news in streetwear, sneakers, fashion, entertainment and music.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Designing the streetwear shopping experience</title><link href="http://happygoodhorse.com/2018/01/01/hbx-find-your-size.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Designing the streetwear shopping experience" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://happygoodhorse.com/2018/01/01/hbx-find-your-size</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happygoodhorse.com/2018/01/01/hbx-find-your-size.html">&lt;p&gt;We kickstarted tackling product returns by analyzing data to validate the top reason for returns: due to wrong size. Through user interviews and testing, we found that this was due to brands using different sizing and the difficulty of using traditional sizing charts. Most shoppers didn’t know their detailed body measurements like chest circumference and shoulder width, but knew their height and weight off the top of their head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How might we help and encourage shoppers to find a more accurate size?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hbx-find-your-size-height-weight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We designed the size recommendation based on what most shoppers knew: their height and weight&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;We designed the size recommendation based on what most shoppers already knew: their height and weight&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To simplify the process, we mapped the body measurements to the height and weight and tested with our coworkers in the office to refine the accuracy. We found that people who had a flat/round belly or broad/slim shoulders produced a wider range of results, so we added those options to the flow and encouraged them to input their body measurements for a more reliable size recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/hbx-find-your-size.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We AB tested the call-to-cation on the product page to determine the most effective design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hbx-find-your-size-saved.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The most effective call-to-action based on AB testing: an underlined link positioned right beneath the size options&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The most effective call-to-action based on AB testing: an underlined link positioned right beneath the size options&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outcome: three months after we launched the size recommendation, returns due to improper sizing dropped by 86%.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We kickstarted tackling product returns by analyzing data to validate the top reason for returns: due to wrong size. Through user interviews and testing, we found that this was due to brands using different sizing and the difficulty of using traditional sizing charts. Most shoppers didn’t know their detailed body measurements like chest circumference and shoulder width, but knew their height and weight off the top of their head.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Designing a simple experience for choosing the right insurance plan</title><link href="http://happygoodhorse.com/2016/11/01/bupa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Designing a simple experience for choosing the right insurance plan" /><published>2016-11-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://happygoodhorse.com/2016/11/01/bupa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://happygoodhorse.com/2016/11/01/bupa.html">&lt;p&gt;Between May and November of 2016, I worked on Bupa Hong Kong’s new website as Art Director at Isobar. I designed the visual interface and worked closely with the UX team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bupa is a healthcare group headquartered in the United Kingdom. It expanded into Hong Kong in 1976 and has been a health insurance and healthcare provision business since. Their audience is professional individuals and companies looking for a healthcare plan for their employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discovery&quot;&gt;Discovery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reviewed feedback on the current site and discovered that &lt;strong&gt;customers found it difficult to find a suitable insurance plan&lt;/strong&gt;. We did an analysis and found several problems: product names were vague and non-descriptive, the wide range of plans and broad categories were hard to browse, and the website wasn’t mobile-optimized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We brainstormed on how to make it easier for customers to find a suitable plan, and proceeded with the idea of &lt;strong&gt;giving recommendations and quotations based on a simple form&lt;/strong&gt;. We added a form on the home page where customers fill in a few fields and immediately get three recommended plans. They can choose to refine the pricing by adding more information and enroll the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-flow.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beginning steps are the simplest, and with each step the flow becomes more specific and there is more information and data input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Input a few pieces of information to receive three recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compare and select a plan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refine the quotation by choosing payment and plan options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Long form for personal details and a series of yes/no health questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Payment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-desktop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Medical insurance plans and quotation engine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We designed the recommended plans view to be in the same style as regular cards, but expanded vertically to show more information. The information is divided into sections and displayed in an underlying grid so the same information can be &lt;strong&gt;easily scanned&lt;/strong&gt; across all three plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early feedback and testing of the wireframes showed that many customers found the forms &lt;strong&gt;long and overwhelming&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to breaking up the long forms into smaller chunks and steps, we tested the idea of using placeholders as labels. Bupa and our team were initially drawn to this idea because it made the forms appear less overwhelming—the forms looked “cleaner” and the reduced vertical space meant less scroll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the density of Traditional Chinese characters, labels are easier to read in a larger size and lighter weight than smaller size and heavier weight. Material Design recommends increasing “Dense scripts” by 1 point from the specified size for English. This adds more vertical space for Chinese form labels, plus &lt;strong&gt;exaggerates the visual density&lt;/strong&gt; when compared to using placeholders as labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, using placeholders as labels create a number of usability problems, as summarized by Katie Sherwin of Nielsen Norman Group. Here are the top three reasons that applied to the forms we were designing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strains short-term memory&lt;/strong&gt;: users have to delete what they wrote to reveal the placeholder label again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users cannot check their input with the label&lt;/strong&gt; (especially important for browsers with autocomplete)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empty vs non-empty fields are less noticeable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-labels.png&quot; alt=&quot;Traditional labels, placeholder labels and float labels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We compromised by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/r/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fmds.is%2Ffloat-label-pattern%2F&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;float labels&lt;/a&gt;. Float labels allow the empty form to appear more clean and less overwhelming, while solving the usability problems of placeholder labels to a certain extent. When asked which form looks less overwhelming, most customers picked the one with float labels over labels on top of fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-form.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enrollment form&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website launched in early 2017. Bupa loved the brand new clean, simple and functional design. The new website increased sales leads by 200% and online purchases by 300%.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Between May and November of 2016, I worked on Bupa Hong Kong’s new website as Art Director at Isobar. I designed the visual interface and worked closely with the UX team.</summary></entry></feed>