<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://tomoslau.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://tomoslau.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-09T23:43:28+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tom Lau</title><subtitle>I'm Tom Lau, a designer based in Hong Kong working with startups and businesses to build amazing products.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">GOGO delivery order experience</title><link href="http://tomoslau.com/gogo-delivery-order-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GOGO delivery order experience" /><published>2019-07-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-07-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/gogovan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tomoslau.com/gogo-delivery-order-experience/">&lt;p&gt;GOGOVAN launched a new crowd-sourced same-day delivery service in 2018 summer. The service targets small-medium businesses with ad-hoc urgent delivery needs in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reducing-oversize-and-overweight-orders&quot;&gt;Reducing oversize and overweight orders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first week of launch, we noticed a high cancellation rate, where 80% of cancellations were due to shippers placing orders with &lt;strong&gt;oversized, overweight or multiple packages&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;process--experience&quot;&gt;Process &amp;amp; experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the problem, I asked the experts from our operations, customer service, engineering and data teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shippers assume our couriers deliver packages using &lt;strong&gt;vans&lt;/strong&gt;,” Jackie, head of customer service, said, “but in reality, our couriers are &lt;strong&gt;walkers&lt;/strong&gt; (couriers who travel on foot and public transport).” This led to oversized, overweight or multiple packages that were physically impossible for a courier to carry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggv-oversize-sketches.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sketches and voting stickers to explore and decide which ideas to test in our prototype&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Sketches and voting stickers to explore and decide which ideas to test in our prototype&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PM Waikit and I wrote out some How Might We’s, made some quick sketches and voted to decide which ideas to test in our prototype. We tested the prototype with five shippers unfamiliar with our service, and all testers understood that courier deliveries are carried out by a walker or biker. They also successfully switched to the van service when tasked to deliver a larger or heavier item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggv-oversize-screens.png&quot; alt=&quot;1. Added package type options to show what kind of packages are acceptable for couriers to deliver. 2. Helper text with a link to direct oversized delivery needs to our van service. 3. An option for oversized packages that direct to our van service.&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;1. Redesigned service icon and label to clarify our couriers’ mode of transport&lt;br /&gt;
	2. Added package type options to show what kind of packages are acceptable for couriers to deliver&lt;br /&gt;
	3. Helper text with a link to direct oversized delivery needs to our van service&lt;br /&gt;
	4. An option for oversized packages that direct to our van service&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-outcome&quot;&gt;The outcome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to scope vs outcome, we decided to implement the new service icon, helper text, oversize/overweight options and not add package type options to the order form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One month after the release, cancellations due to oversized items by new shippers reduced by 37%. Overall cancellation rate dropped 17%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scheduled-delivery&quot;&gt;Scheduled delivery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through interviews with e-commerce shippers and local boutique store visits, we learned that shippers wanted to be able to schedule deliveries for the next day so they can &lt;strong&gt;place multiple orders at the same time without worrying about it the next morning&lt;/strong&gt;. Our customer service team also informed us that many clients found it &lt;strong&gt;difficult to understand the cut-off time for each drop-off option&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;process--experience-1&quot;&gt;Process &amp;amp; experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To improve the clarity of drop-off times, we worked with the operations and marketing team to make the times more memorable by rounding the times to the closest hour and displaying all drop-off options even when they’re not available. We also added helper text to make the cut-off time more transparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;background-color:#F1F5F8;padding: 2rem&quot;&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;max-width:372px;margin:0 auto&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/ggd-do-time-prototype.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Prototype to test the clarity of drop-off options and cut-off times&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tested the prototype with users and they found the helper text most useful in understanding the options. However, some users found the “available if…” helper text on available options confusing, so we decided to only show it when the option is disabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/ggd-scheduling.png&quot; alt=&quot;1. Added package type options to show what kind of packages are acceptable for couriers to deliver. 2. Helper text with a link to direct oversized delivery needs to our van service. 3. An option for oversized packages that direct to our van service.&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;1. Simplified the pick-up time selection for clarity&lt;br /&gt;
	2. Showing unavailable drop-off options in a disabled state with helper text to remind shippers of the cut-off times&lt;br /&gt;
	3. Date picker for scheduling deliveries up to six days in advance&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-outcome-1&quot;&gt;The outcome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After shipping the scheduling feature, the percentage of scheduled orders increased by 270%. Scheduled orders make 20–30% of our daily orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-learned&quot;&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The problem of shippers not understanding our service wasn’t identified during the closed beta period prior to launch because our sales team onboarded each user so they had a good understanding of the service. When new customers started using the service, the problems started to show up. &lt;strong&gt;Test product onboarding with completely new users.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talking to our operations and customer service team gave us valuable insight into the problems we were tackling because they communicated with the shippers frequently. &lt;strong&gt;Talk to people who listen to  our users’ problems regularly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asking for feedback on the product copy made me realize that simple words can be improved to convey more meaning. For example, I learned that there are different words in Chinese for “package” and one of them implies a small package. &lt;strong&gt;Always ask for advice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">GOGOVAN launched a new crowd-sourced same-day delivery service in 2018 summer. The service targets small-medium businesses with ad-hoc urgent delivery needs in Hong Kong.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">HYPEBEAST mobile redesign</title><link href="http://tomoslau.com/hypebeast-mobile-redesign/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HYPEBEAST mobile redesign" /><published>2018-08-12T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-08-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/hypebeast-mobile-redesign</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tomoslau.com/hypebeast-mobile-redesign/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hypebeast.com&quot;&gt;HYPEBEAST&lt;/a&gt; is a media platform for youth culture to get the latest news in streetwear, sneakers, fashion, entertainment and music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to increase our loyal readership by improving the mobile app reading experience. During 2017 and 2018, I redesigned HYPEBEAST’s mobile apps to foster a better reading experience. Below are a few changes we shipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-a-more-familiar-experience-for-both-platforms&quot;&gt;Creating a more familiar experience for both platforms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HYPEBEAST’s Android app was designed to mimic the iOS counterpart. This created an &lt;strong&gt;unfamiliar interactive and visual experience&lt;/strong&gt; for our Android readers, as well as a &lt;strong&gt;reduction in app performance&lt;/strong&gt; due to custom components and animations based on iOS. Furthermore, Google Play refused to feature our app due to several usability and visual issues addressed in the Material Design guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-drops-platforms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Application of Material Design patterns to the Android app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make our app less confusing for our app readers, &lt;strong&gt;we utilized patterns shared by both iOS and Android platforms, while conforming to Human Interface Guidelines and Material Design specs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We used native components and system icons wherever possible.&lt;/strong&gt; By removing custom components and animations, such as the app bar and iOS-style “back” transition, the Android app’s performance increased and felt more snappy and familiar to our readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improving-readability-andfocus&quot;&gt;Improving readability and focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We received feedback from our readers that our app looks dated. This was apparent when compared to our competitors and other apps. Instead of simply following the minimalism trend, we decided to take this opportunity to improve readability and focus as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-home-article.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;News feed and article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We avoided long headlines on images&lt;/strong&gt; for articles where editors and designers don’t have control over placement and styling. Previously, the gradient overlays made images too dark, covered parts of images, and sometimes created undesirable visuals. The revised design allows both headline and image to be clear, and also uses the same assets across mobile, tablet and desktop designs to simplify editors’ workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-style.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visual styling revisited&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We revisited the typography to &lt;strong&gt;create a stronger hierarchy&lt;/strong&gt;. Readers can identify important news and sponsored posts based on prominence. We reduced the complexity of icons to make them more recognizable. We also implemented new color guidelines to improve contrast and meet WCAG guidelines, and a soft 8-point grid to create vertical rhythm, consistent spacing and increased proximity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-components.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;App components&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-natural-and-familiar-gesture-controls&quot;&gt;More natural and familiar gesture controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In usability tests, we noticed readers trying to use certain gesture controls based on their experience with other popular apps, but the app failed to do their desired action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/hb-gestures.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Gesture interactions based on what readers expected&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we learned that many iOS readers didn’t know that tapping on the status bar scrolls to top. Instead, they tried to scroll to top by tapping on the bottom bar again. We added this gesture control to both platforms. We also made sure all the tabs were swipeable, and image galleries can be closed by flicking it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since shipping these updates, our app reviews improved, and the app was featured on Google Play and the App Store. In 2017, we grew from 32k to 73k monthly active users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hb-home-devices.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HYPEBEAST app on mobile and tablet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">HYPEBEAST is a media platform for youth culture to get the latest news in streetwear, sneakers, fashion, entertainment and music.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">HBX size recommendation</title><link href="http://tomoslau.com/hbx-size-recommendation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HBX size recommendation" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/hbx-find-your-size</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tomoslau.com/hbx-size-recommendation/">&lt;p&gt;We kickstarted tackling product returns by analyzing data to validate the top reason for returns: due to wrong size. Through user interviews and testing, we found that this was due to brands using different sizing and the difficulty of using traditional sizing charts. Most shoppers didn’t know their detailed body measurements like chest circumference and shoulder width, but knew their height and weight off the top of their head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How might we help and encourage shoppers to find a more accurate size?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hbx-find-your-size-height-weight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We designed the size recommendation based on what most shoppers knew: their height and weight&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;We designed the size recommendation based on what most shoppers already knew: their height and weight&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To simplify the process, we mapped the body measurements to the height and weight and tested with our coworkers in the office to refine the accuracy. We found that people who had a flat/round belly or broad/slim shoulders produced a wider range of results, so we added those options to the flow and encouraged them to input their body measurements for a more reliable size recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div&gt;
		&lt;video class=&quot;lazy&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/hbx-find-your-size.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/video&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We AB tested the call-to-cation on the product page to determine the most effective design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ratio-4x3&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/hbx-find-your-size-saved.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The most effective call-to-action based on AB testing: an underlined link positioned right beneath the size options&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The most effective call-to-action based on AB testing: an underlined link positioned right beneath the size options&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outcome: three months after we launched the size recommendation, returns due to improper sizing dropped by 86%.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We kickstarted tackling product returns by analyzing data to validate the top reason for returns: due to wrong size. Through user interviews and testing, we found that this was due to brands using different sizing and the difficulty of using traditional sizing charts. Most shoppers didn’t know their detailed body measurements like chest circumference and shoulder width, but knew their height and weight off the top of their head.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jook app</title><link href="http://tomoslau.com/jook/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jook app" /><published>2017-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/jook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tomoslau.com/jook/">&lt;p&gt;Jook is a side project I’ve been working on with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Kahou526&quot;&gt;Lucas Kuan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MaBoXiu&quot;&gt;Matthieu Bodin&lt;/a&gt;. I focus on design, front-end web development, user testing, and data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discovering-the-problem&quot;&gt;Discovering the problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our project spawned from a specific problem my colleagues and I faced during the summer of 2015. Lucas, Matthieu and I worked in a small office room. &lt;strong&gt;We loved playing music on speakers while we worked.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-office.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our office&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The set up was simple. Matthieu hooked up his computer to the speakers, and played music on Spotify. Although we shared similar tastes in music, Lucas and I would make song requests whenever we felt like a change of music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did we feel the urge to change the music?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To share music that we like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To have a sense of control, a voice/opinion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To change the mood by playing something different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks, we sensed that &lt;strong&gt;requesting songs became disruptive to our work.&lt;/strong&gt; We tried sending Spotify links on Slack to make it easier for Matthieu, but it still felt disruptive. We tried using a shared playlist on Spotify, but it didn’t feel spontaneous. &lt;strong&gt;What if we could each queue songs from our own devices without bothering each other?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Four years at art school and I still can’t draw straight lines.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to build an app to do that—a jukebox for our office room that uses Spotify’s API. As we designed and developed the prototype, we realized that we could use the jukebox app outside of the office—for things like parties and startup events that we organized or attended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-flow.png&quot; alt=&quot;Initial host and guest diagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The host is responsible for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hosting the jukebox through the app.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inviting guests by sharing the jukebox link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learns about the jukebox at the event.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opens the link to jukebox on browser (no log-in required to reduce friction), and sees the song currently playing and queued songs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adds songs to the queue and upvote songs added by others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-web.png&quot; alt=&quot;Web app screenshots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a small party, the host can easily tell everyone about the jukebox, and share a link to them through a group chat. At larger events, this becomes more tricky. Strangers are less likely to try something new, so broadcasting it is not as easy. We later learned from hosts that &lt;strong&gt;guests favor using the host’s device&lt;/strong&gt; to add songs instead of using their own. Many requested for a tablet version of the app to make this easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-swhk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We tested Jook at a Startup Weekend event by word of mouth and handouts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;↑ One of our first tests at a Startup Weekend event by word of mouth and handouts (like the one on this table above the Subway napkin).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing&quot;&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tested Jook whenever possible—at the office, events, and parties. Getting organizers to host a jukebox turned out to be easier than we thought. After observing and talking to guests and hosts, this is what we learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users felt the need to keep adding songs&lt;/strong&gt; when their jukebox ran out of songs in the queue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They spent a lot of time &lt;strong&gt;stuck at the search bar&lt;/strong&gt; thinking of what song to add.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They often opened Spotify to find a song from their library, and then went back to Jook to search the song.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At large events, hosts noticed that &lt;strong&gt;guests prefer to walk up to and use the host’s device&lt;/strong&gt; (ie. an iPad) rather than manually typing in the url when a share link is not sent to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features-we-added-prior-to-public-beta&quot;&gt;Features we added prior to public beta&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fallback playlist&lt;/strong&gt;: where the host can select a playlist to fallback on when there are no songs left in the queue, so that the jukebox will never run out of songs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drag-and-drop songs from Spotify&lt;/strong&gt; directly to Jook on web browser.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preview song snippets before adding them to the jukebox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/jook-app.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We added a fallback playlist feature so the jukebox will never run out of songs to play&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also added a prominent “Send Feedback” button to encourage our users to send us valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since releasing Jook, hosts have created more than 500 jukeboxes with over 5,000 guests. We learned several things from our users:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-they-loved&quot;&gt;What they loved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An easy way to play everyone’s favorite music in an environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Voting songs is fun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ease of adding songs on desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-they-struggled-with&quot;&gt;What they struggled with&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finding songs to add on mobile (no drag-and-drop in app or mobile web)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not knowing that a Spotify Premium account is needed to host a jukebox (high drop-off rate on login screen in app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-they-asked-for&quot;&gt;What they asked for&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Downvote to drop unpopular songs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow hosts to remove songs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explicit songs filter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all the users who helped us test the product and gave us amazing feedback. We’re continuously looking at feedback and data from our lovely users, and working towards an update.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Jook is a side project I’ve been working on with Lucas Kuan and Matthieu Bodin. I focus on design, front-end web development, user testing, and data analysis.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bupa website redesign</title><link href="http://tomoslau.com/bupa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bupa website redesign" /><published>2016-11-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://tomoslau.com/bupa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://tomoslau.com/bupa/">&lt;p&gt;Between May and November of 2016, I worked on Bupa Hong Kong’s new website as Art Director at Isobar. I designed the visual interface and worked closely with the UX team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bupa is a healthcare group headquartered in the United Kingdom. It expanded into Hong Kong in 1976 and has been a health insurance and healthcare provision business since. Their audience is professional individuals and companies looking for a healthcare plan for their employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discovery&quot;&gt;Discovery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reviewed feedback on the current site and discovered that &lt;strong&gt;customers found it difficult to find a suitable insurance plan&lt;/strong&gt;. We did an analysis and found several problems: product names were vague and non-descriptive, the wide range of plans and broad categories were hard to browse, and the website wasn’t mobile-optimized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We brainstormed on how to make it easier for customers to find a suitable plan, and proceeded with the idea of &lt;strong&gt;giving recommendations and quotations based on a simple form&lt;/strong&gt;. We added a form on the home page where customers fill in a few fields and immediately get three recommended plans. They can choose to refine the pricing by adding more information and enroll the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-flow.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beginning steps are the simplest, and with each step the flow becomes more specific and there is more information and data input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Input a few pieces of information to receive three recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compare and select a plan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refine the quotation by choosing payment and plan options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Long form for personal details and a series of yes/no health questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Payment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-desktop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Medical insurance plans and quotation engine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We designed the recommended plans view to be in the same style as regular cards, but expanded vertically to show more information. The information is divided into sections and displayed in an underlying grid so the same information can be &lt;strong&gt;easily scanned&lt;/strong&gt; across all three plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early feedback and testing of the wireframes showed that many customers found the forms &lt;strong&gt;long and overwhelming&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to breaking up the long forms into smaller chunks and steps, we tested the idea of using placeholders as labels. Bupa and our team were initially drawn to this idea because it made the forms appear less overwhelming—the forms looked “cleaner” and the reduced vertical space meant less scroll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the density of Traditional Chinese characters, labels are easier to read in a larger size and lighter weight than smaller size and heavier weight. Material Design recommends increasing “Dense scripts” by 1 point from the specified size for English. This adds more vertical space for Chinese form labels, plus &lt;strong&gt;exaggerates the visual density&lt;/strong&gt; when compared to using placeholders as labels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, using placeholders as labels create a number of usability problems, as summarized by Katie Sherwin of Nielsen Norman Group. Here are the top three reasons that applied to the forms we were designing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strains short-term memory&lt;/strong&gt;: users have to delete what they wrote to reveal the placeholder label again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users cannot check their input with the label&lt;/strong&gt; (especially important for browsers with autocomplete)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empty vs non-empty fields are less noticeable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-labels.png&quot; alt=&quot;Traditional labels, placeholder labels and float labels&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We compromised by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/r/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fmds.is%2Ffloat-label-pattern%2F&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;float labels&lt;/a&gt;. Float labels allow the empty form to appear more clean and less overwhelming, while solving the usability problems of placeholder labels to a certain extent. When asked which form looks less overwhelming, most customers picked the one with float labels over labels on top of fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;lazy&quot; data-src=&quot;/assets/bupa-form.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enrollment form&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website launched in early 2017. Bupa loved the brand new clean, simple and functional design. The new website increased sales leads by 200% and online purchases by 300%.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Between May and November of 2016, I worked on Bupa Hong Kong’s new website as Art Director at Isobar. I designed the visual interface and worked closely with the UX team.</summary></entry></feed>